Here we're not going to discuss how to solve these feasibility check exactly.
ここでは これらの実現可能性チェックを正確に解決する方法については説明しません
But I want to give you a few hints about how to
トラジェクトリーのためにいくつかの初期検証を行う方法について
do some initial validation for your trajectory.
いくつかのヒントを与えたいと思います
In order to do so, we're going to neglect
そうするために
the curvature of the road and assume it is locally straight.
道路の曲率を無視して 局所的にまっすぐであると仮定します
Regarding longitudinal acceleration, we make
縦方向の加速に関しては
the additional assumption that our heading is pretty much aligned with the road.
方位が道路とほぼ一致しているという付加的な仮定をしています
This allows us to say that S doubled dots is the longitude acceleration of the car.
Sの2ドットが車の縦方向の加速度だと言えます
Therefore, we need to check that at any point of the trajectory,
トラジェクトリーのどの時点でも 次のことを確認する必要があります
this acceleration is less than
この加速度は
the maximum acceleration that the engine would need to supply,
エンジンが供給する必要のある最大加速度より小さく
and more than the maximum braking deceleration of the car.
車両の最大ブレーキ減速度を超えています
Right now, this could be a fixed value.
今のところ これは固定値の場合があります
In real life however,
しかし 実生活では
this should probably be computed using information about the friction of the road.
道路の摩擦についての情報を使って計算するべきです
Similarly, for lateral acceleration,
同様に 横方向の加速度については
we can check that all d double dot values are less than
すべての d 二重ドットの値が
a fixed lateral acceleration value that can be set for comfort,
快適さ
or to avoid any risk of rollover in our car.
または 車の横転の危険を避けるために設定できる横方向の固定値である値よりも小さいことを確認できます
Regarding steering angle, the bicycle model tells us that there's
ステアリング角に関して 自転車モデルは
a nice relationship between the steering angle of
自動車のステアリング角と曲率円の半径の間には
the car and the radius of the circle of curvature,
良い関係があることを示しています
where L is the distance between the wheel axis and R is the circle radius.
ここで L は車輪の距離で R は円の半径です
The curvature is then given by this formula,
曲率は次式で求めることができるため
and therefore the maximum curvature allowed at
トラジェクトリーの任意の点で許容される最大曲率は
any point of the trajectory is given by this equation.
この式で求めることができます
If you remember, in the reading assignment about [inaudible]
覚えていれば [無音の]
the curvature for path is defined like this,
についての読みの割り当てでは 経路の曲率は次のように定義されます
where Δφi is the heading difference between two points of
ここで
the trajectory and Δχi is the distance between them.
Δφi はトラジェクトリーの 2 点間の方位差 Δχi はそれらの間の距離です
Finally the velocity is checked against
最後に 速度は地図または挙動レイヤによって指定された
values specified by the map or the behavioral layer.
値に対してチェックされます
For example, we could use the speed limit of the road in most cases.
たとえば ほとんどの場合 道路の制限速度を使用できます
That gives us a maximal velocity but also sometimes,
最大速度を使用できますが 時々
we need a minimal velocity like on
高速道路のように
highways where we don't want to drive too slow or we're backing up,
遅く走りたくない または バックしない場合は
negative S dot is not allowed.
負の S ドットは許されません